apptopia.com 2019-04-27

# Privacy Policy | Apptopia

### Last Updated: November 15, 2018

This privacy policy (" **Privacy Policy** ") describes how Apptopia, Inc. and its related companies (" **Apptopia,** " " **we,** " and " **us** "), acting as data controllers, collect, use and share information when a person or business (" **you,** " " **your** ") accesses our website, uses the Apptopia Chrome extension or uses in any manner any Apptopia mobile application, product, service, feature, technology, content, or website (collectively, the " **Services** ").

BY CLICKING A BOX INDICATING YOUR ACCEPTANCE, BY USING OR BY REGISTERING TO THE SERVICES, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ, UNDERSTAND AND AGREE TO BE LEGALLY BOUND BY THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND ARE CONSENTING TO APPTOPIA'S PRACTICES RELATED TO YOUR INFORMATION AND THIS PRIVACY POLICY. YOUR CONTINUED USE OF THIS SITE OR SERVICES AFTER APPTOPIA MAKES A CHANGE IS DEEMED TO BE ACCEPTANCE OF THOSE CHANGES.

YOU REPRESENT AND WARRANT THAT (I) YOU ARE 16 YEARS OF AGE OR OLDER, AND (II) YOU HAVE READ AND UNDERSTOOD THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE, WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND PRACTICES, DO NOT USE, VISIT, REGISTER OR OTHERWISE ACCESS THE SITE, THE SERVICES AND CONTENT CONTAINED ON THE SITE OR SERVICES.

## WHAT WE COLLECT

We get information about you in a range of ways.

### Information You Give Us.

We collect your account data, which may include your‎ name, postal address, email address, phone number, username and password (“ **Account Data** ”). The Account Data may be processed for the purposes of providing to you our Services and of ensuring their security, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you.

We may process information included in your personal profile, which may include your demographic information, location, time zone and website (“ **Profile Data** ”). The Profile Data may be processed for the purposes of providing you a better user experience when using the Services.

We may process financial information such as credit card or PayPal information when you order Services in order to facilitate the processing of payments (“ **Payment Information** ”).

We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us (“ **Correspondence Data** ”). The Correspondence Data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you, provide customer service and record-keeping.

### Information Automatically Collected.

We automatically log information about you, your computer or your mobile device when you visit our website or access the Services and we collect information about the domains of the websites you visit through the Apptopia Chrome extension (“ **Usage Data** ”). For example, when visiting our website, we log your computer operating system type, browser type, browser language, the website you visited before browsing to our website, pages you viewed, how long you spent on a page, access times and information about your use of and actions on our website. If you use a mobile device to access the Services we may collect device information (such as your mobile device ID, model and manufacturer), operating system, version information and IP address. The Usage Data is processed for the purpose of providing our Services.

### Information We Get From Others.

We may get information about you from other sources. We may add this to information we get from our website or your use of the Services

In particular, we may use third-party service providers such as Google Analytics to provide anonymous site metrics and other analytics services (the “ **Analytics Data** ”). These third parties may use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies to collect information, such as your IP address, identifiers associated with your device, other applications on your device, the browsers you use to access our Services, webpages viewed, time spent on webpages, links clicked, and conversion information (e.g., transactions entered into). The Analytics Data may be used by us and third-party service providers on our behalf to analyze and track usage of and better understand how you use the Services. You can find information about Google Analytics’ privacy policy at [https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245.](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)

When you connect your iTunes Connect and Google Play accounts with our Services, we retrieve key metrics information about your mobile application, such as downloads, installs and uninstalls, advertising revenues and in app purchases (the “ **App Metrics Data** ”). We then use anonymized, aggregate trends of the App Metrics Data to optimize our Service offering to our clients.

## SHARING OF INFORMATION

We may share Personally Identifiable Information as follows:

  * We will only share Account Data or Profile Data with your explicit consent and you have the right to withdraw this consent at any time by simply sending us an email at [privacy@apptopia.com](mailto:privacy@apptopia.com). For example, you may let us share personally identifiable information with others for their own marketing uses. We would immediately stop sharing your Account Data or Profile Data upon receipt of your email instructing us to do so.
  * We may share Account Data or Profile Data for legal, protection, and safety purposes.
    * We may share information to comply with laws.
    * We may share information to respond to lawful requests and legal processes.
    * We may share information to protect the rights and property of Apptopia, Inc., our agents, customers, and others. This includes enforcing our agreements, policies, and terms of use.
    * We may share information in an emergency. This includes protecting the safety of our employees and agents, our customers, or any person.
  * We may disclose Usage Data and Analytics Data to a variety of third party service providers insofar as reasonably necessary to improve the functionalities of the Services. For example, we may disclose Service Data to obtain useful analytics, provide in-app support to mobile app users, determine location data and provide search engine functionality to our users.
  * We share App Metrics Data with our clients for their own uses.
  * We may share information with those who need it to do work for us. This disclosure will be subject to these third parties entering into confidentiality covenants with respect to your information.
  * We may share personally identifiable information when we do a business deal, or negotiate a business deal, involving the sale or transfer of all or a part of our business or assets. These deals can include any merger, financing, acquisition, or bankruptcy transaction or proceeding. In this event, we will notify you before your personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

## INFORMATION CHOICES AND CHANGES

Our marketing emails tell you how to “opt-out.” If you opt out, we may still send you non-marketing emails. Non-marketing emails include emails about your accounts and our business dealings with you.

You can typically remove and reject cookies from our website with your browser settings. Many browsers are set to accept cookies until you change your settings. If you remove or reject our cookies, it could affect how our website works for you.

You may access, review, change, delete and update the Account Data, Profile Data, Payment Information and Correspondence Data at any time via our website, by email at [privacy@apptopia.com](mailto:privacy@apptopia.com) or otherwise via the Services.

You may choose to close or request that we delete your Apptopia account at any time. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to remove the Account Data, Profile Data, Payment Information and Correspondence Data, although some information may be retained. For example, some information may be retained on a backup server or media, which is necessary to help ensure the continued availability of the Services.

You have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

## LINKS

The Services may contain references, frames, links and other functionality that connect with certain internet websites, applications or resources, or social media platform or services maintained by third parties (" **Links** "). These Links are provided for your convenience only. You acknowledge and agree that we are not responsible or liable for: (i) the availability or accuracy of such websites or resources; or (ii) the content, features, products, services, privacy policies or terms of service on or available from such websites or resources. Links to such websites or resources do not imply any endorsement by us of such websites or resources or the content, products, or services available from such websites or resources, or its owners, sponsors or operators.

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Services This Services may contain links to other websites not operated or controlled by us (“ **Third Party Sites** ”). The Privacy Policy does not apply to Third Party Sites.

You acknowledge sole responsibility for and assume all risk arising from your use of any such websites or resources or the content, products or services on or available from such websites or resources, privacy policies or terms of service of any other third party, including, without limitation, any social media platform.

## SECURITY

We are very serious about keeping your personally identifiable information safe. We provide reasonable and appropriate security measures to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and upon receipt. However, the Internet is not a secure environment and we do not warrant that personally identifiable information may not be accessed, copied, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach despite the security protections undertaken by us. We cannot guarantee the absolute security of your personally identifiable information. No data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have any questions about security on our website and the Services, you can email us at [privacy@apptopia.com](mailto:privacy@apptopia.com).

## Cookies and Web Beacons.

We may use the standard cookie feature of major browser applications and third-party providers, or employ internally developed cookies and tracking codes, that allows Apptopia to store a small piece of data on a User’s computer (or any other device used to access the Services, including a mobile device) about the User’s use of the Site. It’s a text-only string of information that allows us to distinguish you from other Users, but not in a personally identifiable way. We do capture personally identifiable information in cookies or use cookies to mine personally identifiable information. If you do not want us to use cookies, you must disable them in your browser. If you choose to do so, you may still use the Site, but your ability to use some of areas and features of the Site may be limited.

We employ technologies such as clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons), tags and scripts to help us better manage content by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track online usage metrics. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer or device, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We do tie the information gathered by clear gifs to personally identifiable information.

## POLICY TOWARD CHILDREN

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16, and you must be 16 years of age or older in order to establish an account with Apptopia or otherwise use the Services. In the event you become aware that an individual under the age of 16 has enrolled, please contact us immediately at privacy@apptopia.com and we will remove their information from our system immediately.

## EU-US PRIVACY SHIELD FRAMEWORK INFORMATION

Apptopia complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personally identifiable information transferred from the European Union to the United States. Apptopia has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

Individuals may file a complaint concerning Apptopia’s processing of their personally identifiable information. Apptopia will take steps to remedy issues arising out of its alleged failure to comply with the Privacy Shield Principles. Individuals may contact Apptopia as specified below about complaints regarding the company’s personally identifiable information practices.

If an Individuals’ complaint cannot be resolved through Apptopia's internal processes, Apptopia will cooperate with JAMS pursuant to the JAMS International Mediation Rules, available on the JAMS website at www.jamsadr.com/international-mediation-rules. Individuals may launch a Privacy Shield case by visiting <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield>. JAMS mediation may be commenced as provided for in the relevant JAMS rules. The mediator may propose any appropriate remedy, such as deletion of the relevant personally identifiable information, publicity for findings of noncompliance, payment of compensation for losses incurred as a result of noncompliance, or cessation of processing of the personally identifiable information of the Individual who brought the complaint. The mediator or the individual also may refer the matter to the U.S. Federal Trade Commission, which has Privacy Shield investigatory and enforcement powers over Apptopia. Under certain circumstances, Individuals also may be able to invoke binding arbitration to address complaints about Apptopia’s compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles.

## CONTACT INFORMATION

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or its implementation, you may contact Apptopia via [privacy@apptopia.com](mailto:privacy@apptopia.com) or at the following address: Apptopia, Inc., 132 Lincoln St, 3rd Floor, Boston, MA 02111.

## CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We may change this privacy policy. If we make any changes, we will change the Last Updated date above.
